The real world and the animated world collide.
Enchanted is a comedy, family, fantasy film directed by Kevin Lima.
The beautiful princess Giselle is banished by an evil queen from her magical, musical animated
land and finds herself in the gritty reality of the streets of modern-day Manhattan.
Shocked by this strange new environment that doesn't operate on a "happily ever after"
basis, Giselle is now adrift in a chaotic world badly in need of enchantment.
But when Giselle begins to fall in love with a charmingly flawed divorce lawyer who has come to her aid - even though she is already
promised to a perfect fairy tale prince back home - she has to wonder: Can a storybook view of romance survive in the real world?
Giselle, played by Amy Adams.
Robert Philip, played by Patrick Dempsey.
Prince Edward, played by James Marsden.
Nathaniel, played by Timothy Spall.
Nancy Tremaine, played by Idina Menzel.
Morgan Philip, played by Rachel Covey.
Enchanted is a 2007 American live-action animated musical fantasy romantic
comedy film directed by Kevin Lima and written by Bill Kelly.
Co-produced by Walt Disney Pictures, Josephson Entertainment, and Right Coast Productions, the film stars Amy Adams, Patrick
Dempsey, James Marsden, Timothy Spall, Idina Menzel, and Susan Sarandon, with Julie Andrews as the narrator.
It focuses on an archetypal Disney Princess-to-be named Giselle, who is exiled from her animated world into the
live-action world of the New York City metropolitan area, where she falls in love with a divorce lawyer.
The film is both an homage to and a self-parody of Disney's animated features, making numerous references to past works
through the combination of live-action filmmaking, traditional animation, and computer-generated imagery.
It also marks the return of traditional animation to a Disney feature film after the
company's decision to move entirely to computer animation in 2004.
Composer Alan Menken and lyricist Stephen Schwartz, who had written songs for previous Disney films,
wrote and produced the songs of Enchanted, and Menken also composed the film's score.
The animated sequences were produced at James Baxter Animation in Pasadena, while
filming of the live-action segments took place around New York City.
Enchanted premiered at the London Film Festival on October 20, 2007, and went
into its wide release in the United States on November 21.
It was critically well-received, established Adams as a leading lady, and
earned more than $340 million worldwide at the box office.
It won three Saturn Awards, Best Fantasy Film, Best
Actress for Adams and Best Music for Menken.
Enchanted also received two nominations at the 65th Golden Globe Awards and
three Best Original Song nominations at the 80th Academy Awards.
This is the first Walt Disney Pictures film to be distributed under the Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures banner after Disney retired the Buena Vista brand from its distribution division.
A sequel, Disenchanted, was released on Disney+ on November 18, 2022.
The film explores themes of princess, new york city, magic, fairy tale, poison.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.